well you made it the end of the series
好吧 你让这部系列剧结束了
you've watched 14 videos so uh before I
你已经看了14个视频了 所以在我之前
show you how to turn the image sequence
演示如何将图像序列
into a final video I do want to say
最后一段视频中 我确实想说
congratulations because um everyone says
祝贺你 因为 嗯 大家都说
they want to learn new skills and very
他们想要学习新的技能 而且非常
few people actually want to put in the
几乎没有人真的想要把
time so if you're watching this you have
时间 所以如果你在看这个 你有
clearly put in the time so I mean that
显然投入了时间 所以我的意思是
truly well done now if you are able to
真正的做得好Now 如果您能够
go from this series and then go off and
从这个系列赛开始 然后离开 然后
create and get what you want out of
创造并获得你想要的东西
blender then fantastic uh but what I've
搅拌机 太棒了 但我所拥有的
learned over the years is that there is
多年来了解到的是 有
a percentage of people who want more
想要更多的人的百分比
they want to know what tutorials to
他们想知道要提供哪些教程
watch next to level up their career so I
观看NeXT来提升他们的职业生涯 这样我
am in the process of creating a blender
我正在制作一台搅拌机
course for beginners M special so this
为初学者开设的课程M很特别 所以这个
is going to be for you guys essentially
基本上是为你们准备的
people who finished this course and then
完成这门课程的人然后
they want more they want to know uh how
他们想要更多 他们想知道 呃 如何
do they do other parts of blender Beyond
他们做搅拌机的其他部分吗？
just a donut so it's not available yet
只是一个甜甜圈 所以现在还没有
but I'm looking to release it in early
不过 我希望能早点发布
2024 if I can um so if you want to be
如果我可以 嗯 如果你想的话
notified when it is available uh click
当它可用时通知 呃点击
the link in the description and you can
描述中的链接 您可以
join a separate email list just for this
加入一个单独的电子邮件列表就是为了这个
course to be notified once it uh is
一旦它呃是 课程将被通知
available it's not going to be free it
它是可用的 不是免费的
is going to be a paid course um but it
将是一门付费课程 嗯 但它
is uh yeah for people who really want to
是对那些真的想要
take this seriously and make a career
认真对待这一点 然后开创自己的事业
out of it that is for you so with that
这是给你的 就是这样
out of the way now on to the tutorial if
现在请不要使用本教程 如果
you followed the last part correctly you
你正确地理解了最后一部分 对吗？
should find inside this
应该会在这里面找到
folder 160 Tiff files which are you know
文件夹160 Tiff文件你知道哪些是
you can open them individually and look
您可以单独打开它们并查看
at the images but if you want to create
但如果您想要创建
a video then this is what you do if
一段视频 这就是你要做的 如果
you're using this as part of another
你把这当作另一件事
video project um then you might be using
视频项目嗯 那么您可能正在使用
software like Premier I know that's not
像Premier这样的软件我知道那不是
all of you but I'll just quickly show
你们所有人 但我很快就会展示
you for those who want to use Premiere
对于那些想要使用Premiere的人
instead you just click on the first
相反 您只需点击第一个
image and then check image sequence uh
然后再检查图像序列呢
that'll import it and then just drag
这将导入它 然后拖动
that into a new sequence and there you
变成了一个新的序列 而你
go and then you can just import uh sorry
去吧 然后你就可以进口了 呃 对不起
export that as you would anything in
将其导出 就像您在
Premiere or edit it Etc but if you want
首映或编辑等 但如果你想
to use blender if you want to go the
使用搅拌机 如果你想去
free route there is actually a video
免费路线实际上有一段视频
editor inside of blender now you can
搅拌器内的编辑器现在您可以
access it from uh inside here um but I
从这里 呃 里面 嗯 但是我
actually find it easier and better to
实际上发现更容易和更好的是
just create a new blender instance so
只需创建一个新的搅拌器实例即可
for that I go file new and then you can
为此 我会提交新的文件 然后你就可以
go General but actually if you go video
去一般 但实际上 如果你去视频
editing um then that will just set it up
编辑 嗯 然后这将只是设置它
for you ready to go and it'll just it
为你准备好离开 这就是它
saves a bunch of time this isn't like a
节省了很多时间这不像是
special version of blender or anything
特殊版本的搅拌机或任何东西
when you choose this like if you want to
当你像这样选择的时候 如果你想
use you know the standard blender layout
使用你知道的标准搅拌机布局
or whatever it's still there it's just
或者不管它还在哪里 它只是
it's created this video like this screen
它创建了这个视频 就像这个屏幕
layout and everything is already
布局和一切都已经
configured and ready to go for you
已配置好 随时可以为您服务
anyways so down here this is your video
不管怎样 下面这是你的视频
editor this is the sequenc as it's
编辑：这是按顺序排列的序列
called and then up here is going to show
呼唤着 然后在这里将会展示
you the video that it's uh displaying so
你的视频 呃 它展示的是
the first thing we need to do is load in
我们需要做的第一件事是加载
that image sequence so shift a hotkey
该图像序列因此移动了热键
works all over blender choose image
适用于所有搅拌机选择图像
sequence navigate to that folder where
序列导航到该文件夹
you have uh all of these Tiff files and
你有 呃 所有这些Tiff文件和
unlike Premier where you select the
与Premier不同 在Premier中选择
first one and then import that this one
先买一个 然后再导入这个
you need to select all of them so the
您需要将它们全部选中 以便
hotkey is just a to select everything
热键只是一个选择一切的工具
hot Keys work everywhere across blender
热键在搅拌机上随处可用
and then go add image strip aha now you
然后去添加图像条啊哈 现在你
can see we've got this strip at the
可以看到我们有这个带子在
bottom here and if we hit the space bar
在这下面 如果我们按空格键
we should see at the top the uh image
我们应该在最上面看到这个图像
sequence playing awesome now it looks a
序列播放很棒 现在看起来像
little slow and you'll see actually in
稍微慢一点 你就会看到实际上
the top left hand cornner it's playing
它正在播放的左上角
at 24 frames a second and that's because
每秒24帧 这是因为
although we set it up as 30 frames a
尽管我们将其设置为30帧/秒
second we just rendered that into the uh
第二 我们只是把它渲染到呃
image sequence doesn't know what the
图像序列不知道
frame rate is the only reason we did
帧速率是我们这么做的唯一原因
that was so that when you're playing the
这就是说 当你在玩
animation in the viewport it's actually
视口中的动画它实际上是
at the correct speed but to set it up
以正确的速度 但要设置它
here uh you set your frame rate here
在这里 呃 您在这里设置您的帧速率
from uh 24 to 30 and now if you play it
从24点到30点 现在如果你玩它
you'll see it's going at 30 frames a
你会看到它以30帧/秒的速度
second it's a little faster it's a
第二 它稍微快了一点 这是一个
little smoother and uh it looks good
稍微光滑一点 呃 看起来很好
great now you can see it just kind of
太好了 现在你可以看到它了
kind of ends right just goes into like
就这样结束了就像
blank nothing and we don't want that I
什么都不是 我们不想要那个我
want to really hold on this end frame
想要真正抓住这一端的框架
because this is the important frame
因为这是一个重要的框架
where all the donuts are revealed at the
在那里所有的甜甜圈都在
end there and it's really easy to extend
在那里结束 扩展起来非常容易
the last frame you just click on the end
最后一帧 你只需点击结尾
of that strip at the bottom there till
底部的那条带子 直到
it lights up white and then you can
它亮起白色 然后你就可以
either click and drag out or hit the
要么单击并向外拖动 要么点击
hotkey g um to grab and we can just move
抓起热键胶水 我们就可以走了
it all the way to the end so 250 that's
它一直走到最后 所以250美元
what the uh the final like the frame
什么 呃 决赛是什么样子的框架
range here is right if you want it to be
这里的范围是正确的 如果你想的话
longer or shorter you can change it
更长或更短 你可以改变它
there but I'm going to keep it at 250 so
好的 但我会把它保持在250
that means now it gets to the end and
这意味着现在它走到了尽头
then it just holds here and let you soak
然后它就会保持在这里 让你浸泡
it in soak in those uh those donuts um
浸泡在那些呃那些甜甜圈里
cool and this is fine you could export
酷 这很好 你可以出口
this but I also just want to have a nice
但我也只想好好玩一玩
fade out at the end because why not just
在最后淡出 为什么不干脆
learn about something in the video
了解视频中的一些内容
sequence editor um to do that I'm going
序列编辑 嗯 要做这个 我要去
to go shift a and then add in a color
将a移位 然后添加颜色
and and the color is already set up as
并且颜色已经设置为
black so that's fine so I'm just
黑色 所以很好 所以我只是
dragging it over the end here and you
把它拖到尽头 然后你
can see it just jumps to the color CU
可以看到它只是跳到颜色CU
that's now over the top of that other
现在它在另一个上面
strip so it's it's reading top to bottom
剥离 所以它是从上到下阅读的
so it's black is over the top and uh
所以它是黑色的 在上面 嗯
instead of it being a jump cut to black
它不是跳到黑色的剪辑
we obviously want to fade it so to do
我们显然想淡化它 这样做
that just click that that uh strip there
只需点击那里的那个呃条带
and then say shift a and then say fade
然后说Shift a 然后说淡出
fade in and you'll see it's uh it's hard
淡入 你会发现 呃 这很难
to read here from this cuz it's got like
在这里阅读 因为它就像
black at the bottom but there is a
底部是黑色的 但有一个
actually can I do
实际上我能做到吗？
that uh I'm using the same uh hotkey
我用的是同一个 呃热键
control middle Mouse Button as when
将鼠标中键控制为时
we're using the graph editor but you can
我们使用的是图形编辑器 但您可以
see there is like a slight uh like a
看那里有一种轻微的呃像一种
little ramp up like that it's just
像这样的小斜坡 只是
showing you it's fading in um but there
向你展示它正在褪色 嗯 但在那里
you go that's the fade in uh effect
你走吧 这就是淡出的效果
there and what that is doing is it's
在那里 它正在做的是它
just created um a key frame animation
刚刚创建了一个关键帧动画
for this opacity slider to just do a
对于此不透明度滑块 只需执行
very quick uh fade in there um but there
非常快 呃 在那里褪色 嗯 但是在那里
you go so now that's it that's what we
你走吧 现在就是这样 这就是我们
want this is what we want to form into a
这就是我们想要形成的
video file which we could upload to
我们可以上传到的视频文件
Youtube or Instagram or whatever so to
YouTube或Instagram或其他任何东西
create that here in your output settings
在您的输出设置中创建它
you want to again choose a folder that
您想要再次选择一个文件夹
you want to save it to I usually save it
你想把它保存到我通常会保存它
inside of the folder with the frames and
在包含框架和框架的文件夹内
I just call it video and then say accept
我把它叫做视频 然后说接受
now because we uh set this up as a new
现在因为我们呃把这个设置成一个新的
video editing file it's automatically
视频编辑文件它是自动
set the file format for us as
为我们设置文件格式为
ffmpeg video and this is actually the
Ffmpeg视频 这实际上是
most flexible I've never needed Avi jpeg
最灵活的是我从来不需要avi jpeg
or raw it just creates those ginormous
或者生的 它只会创造出那些巨大的
gigabyte files that you can never do
千兆字节的文件 你永远都做不到
anything with anyway so ffmpeg is the
任何带有这样的ffmpeg的东西都是
one you want because it's got the most
你想要的 因为它有最多
options um and go underneath encoding
选项um和go在编码下面
and this is where you'll find all of
在这里你会发现所有的
your video settings um for encoding so
您的视频设置用于编码 因此
the container that is your like think of
你喜欢的容器想起来了
it as the file extension right so if
它作为文件扩展名正确 所以如果
it's a mob file that would be QuickTime
这是一个暴徒文件 应该是QuickTime
if it is a MKV file that annoying format
如果它是令人讨厌格式MKV文件
that premere can't read and it's
普雷米尔不识字 而且它
supposed to be better than MP4s but
应该比MP4好 但是
nothing can read it except VLC anyways
不管怎样 除了VLC 没有人能读到它
that would be Metro metosa metosa is the
那将是Metro Metosa Metosa是
the one webm that's like a format that
唯一一个WebM就像一种格式
is becoming more common online you could
在网上变得越来越普遍 你可以
use that anyways we're going to use MP4
不管怎样 我们还是要用MP4
so that's MPEG 4 uh because that's the
这就是MPEG4 呃 因为这是
most common one that most people need
大多数人需要的最常见的一种
video codak we're going to leave it at
视频Codak我们将把它留在
the default F sorry h264 is
默认的F对不起H264是
fine now uh you're if you're used to
现在好了 如果你习惯了的话
like all these settings of bit rates and
像所有这些比特率设置和
all that you can go into that just by
你可以通过以下方式进入其中
setting like constant bit rate and you
像恒定比特率和您的设置
can change all this but I usually just
可以改变这一切但我通常只是
choose one of the uh think of these as
选择一个 呃 把这些想象成
like presets right so high quality is
就像预置一样 高质量是
probably good enough for most people if
可能对大多数人来说足够好了 如果
you want to go even higher quality
你想要更高的质量
perceptually lossless will mean it's
感知上的无损将意味着它
almost the highest quality possible
几乎是最好的质量
possible so there's no loss uh lossless
有可能 所以没有损失 呃 无损
would put it at no loss at all so it's
会让它毫无损失 所以它
like the highest quality I don't think
像最高质量的 我不认为
you ever need that like perceptually
你曾经有过这样的感觉吗？
lossless is probably fine for like more
无损可能对更多的人来说是可以的
than every case you would need right so
比你需要的每一个案子都要好
perceptually lossless and that's it um
感知无损 就是这样 嗯
oh audio we don't have any audio if you
哦 音频我们没有音频 如果你
wanted to you could add in sound here if
想要在这里添加声音 如果
you wanted to we don't have audio so I'm
你想 我们没有音频 所以我
going to set the audio codc to no audio
正在将音频编解码器设置为无音频
I don't think it makes a differ to the
我不认为这与
output but anyway and uh that's it so
输出 但不管怎样 呃 就是这样
now what do you do to export this the
现在 您要怎么做才能将此导出
same as before it's render animation and
与之前相同的渲染动画和
what this does is it just chews through
它的作用是它只会咬穿
those frames in the sequence and you can
序列中的这些帧 您可以
see at the bottom there how fast it's
在底部看 它有多快
going and it's going to fade out Boop
走了 它就会淡出 砰
and that's it so the reason it did that
这就是它这么做的原因
by the way is like cuz like how would it
顺便说一句 就像这样 会怎么样呢？
know like not to render from the camera
知道不喜欢从相机中渲染
cuz we just said render animation it's
因为我们刚刚说过渲染动画
because in your oh where is it way at
因为在你的哦 它在哪里？
the bottom there on my face we've got
我脸上的底部 我们得到了
postprocessing and it's set to sequencer
后处理 并设置为Sequencer
right and if it detects anything in your
好的 如果它在你的电脑里发现了什么
sequencer if it detects anything in this
定序器如果它在这个
strip here it will then render this
在这里剥离它将呈现这个
instead of what is in the camera so
而不是摄像机里的东西 所以
that's how it knows to use those frames
这就是它知道如何使用这些框架的原因
instead of random anyways all to say
而不是随意的 无论如何都是说
look we have Al
听着 我们有艾尔
video playing nicely holds oh soak it up
视频播放得很好 哦 好好享受吧
look at them Donuts Fade Out T so well
看他们甜甜圈淡出的如此之好
done you did it congratulations you made
你做到了吗？祝贺你成功了
it to the end of the series if you want
如果你想看的话就把它放到这个系列的结尾
a challenge ooh why not create some dut
挑战哦 为什么不创造一些DUT呢
variations you could change the color of
您可以更改颜色的变体
the icing and then model some
结冰 然后再做一些模型
star-shaped sprinkles and then you've
星形的点缀 然后你就有了
got a patriotic dut scene M you could
有一个爱国的哑巴场景M你可以
use the polygon add-on to import some of
使用多边形加载项导入一些
our free candles and then some Moonlight
我们的免费蜡烛和一些月光
for for a moody candl light dut scene
为一个喜怒无常的烛光尘埃场景
you could experiment with some different
你可以尝试一些不同的
marble textures there's a lot there you
大理石纹理有很多你
could make the sprinkles gold you could
你可以让洒水变成金色
add in some whiskey glasses a serving
加一些威士忌酒杯 一份
board for a high class expensive dut
高级贵重帆布的冲浪板
looking scene you could decorate it with
你可以用来装饰它的场景
fruit and palm tree models for a
水果和棕榈树模型
tropical themed dut scene or you could
热带主题尘土场景或者你可以
add in some pumpkins change the colors
加入一些南瓜改变颜色
around and you've got a full themed dut
你就有了一个完整的主题DUT
scene there's a lot that you could do so
场景你可以这样做的有很多
have a stack have a go at it and try to
让一堆人试着去做 并尝试
elevate this and make the dut scene your
提升这一点 让尘土场景成为你的
own cuz that's where the real learning
因为那才是真正学习的地方
comes in otherwise thank you so much for
否则就进来了 非常感谢你
watching and I will see you in a future
看着我 我会在未来见到你